<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development environment on Programming project 2023-24</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/</link><description>Recent content in Development environment on Programming project 2023-24</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hierarchical file system</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/files/</guid><description>Hierarchical file system # Tree # Most operating system expose files as a tree (or possibly several trees for Windows).
Definition. A (nonempty) tree is either:
a single node (called a leaf), or a node with one or several children that are trees. In this tree, non-leaf nodes are directories, and the leaves can be files, executables, links, empty directories, etc. For instance:
├── bin │ ├── echo │ └── .</description></item><item><title>Backup</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/backup/</guid><description>Backup # Make sure that your work does not depend on your laptop. You should be able to resume your work easily on another computer if your laptop gets lost, damaged, etc.
You should also be able to recover your data if you accidentally delete it from your hard drive.
Which information to back up # As a priority, make sure that there exist copies (outside of your hard drive) of:</description></item><item><title>Software management</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/install/</guid><description>Software management # Dependencies # As a developer, you frequently need to download, install and/or update:
libraries used in your projects (called dependencies), core programming utilities, such as a compiler or interpreter for a given programming language, a package manager, etc. tools for software development: editor, debugger, visualization tool, etc. These programs have their own dependencies, that have their own dependencies, etc. And two programs may depend on different versions of a same third program.</description></item><item><title>Operating system</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/os/</guid><description>Operating system (OS) # Your computer does not bind you to one OS. You can run multiple OSs on the same computer by:
partitioning your disk, or booting from an external drive, or using virtualisation. Depending on what you are developing, one operating system may be more convenient than another.
We review below some of the benefits and drawbacks of developing under Windows, macOS and Linux.
Windows # Benefits and drawbacks # Here are some benefits of using Windows as your OS for software development:</description></item><item><title>Requirements for this course</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/requirements/</guid><description>Requirements for this course # For this course, you will need:
Git Version 2.2 or higher A Java Development Kit (JDK) for Java 17 (e.g. openJDK) Maven Version 3.6 or higher In addition, if you choose the board game as project, you will need:
Gradle Version 7.2 or higher Again, we recommend using a package manager to install these programs if possible.
For Windows users. Maven is not available on the winget repository.</description></item><item><title>IDE</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/ide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/ide/</guid><description>Integrated development environment (IDE) # An IDE is an application that consists of a source code editor with additional functionalities such as a debugger or build automation.
For this course, you can use any IDE (or enhanced code editor) for Java with at least the following features:
a debugger navigation to variable/class/interface declaration and usage, variable/class/interface renaming, Maven integration, Gradle integration if you choose the board game as your project.</description></item><item><title>Text editor</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/text_editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/text_editor/</guid><description>Text editor # A text editor allows you to edit plain (i.e. non-formatted) text. A text editor can open any file produced with a text editor (and more), regardless of the file&amp;rsquo;s extension.
In this sense, Microsoft Word is not a text editor (neither are Apple Pages or LibreOffice Writer).
Most operating systems comes with one or several text editor(s) pre-installed, such as Notepad++ (Windows), TextEdit (macOS), gedit (default Ubuntu), etc.</description></item><item><title>Evaluation environment</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/eval/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/eval/</guid><description>Evaluation environment # The evaluation environment for your project is a virtual machine (with Ubuntu 20) deployed on Microsoft Azure. You are not supposed to develop on this machine, but your project must run in this environment to be evaluated.
Each student gets his or her own clone of the original machine. Maven, Gradle, git and a Java 17 JDK are already installed. You will also be granted administrator rights, so that you can install additional software (if any) needed to run your project.</description></item><item><title>Terminal</title><link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/terminal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/env/sections/terminal/</guid><description>Terminal # Using a terminal can be necessary during development, in order to execute a program that does not have a graphical user interface (GUI).
But even when a GUI is available, a Command Line Interface (CLI) can still be the preferred way to interact with some programs. Possible benefits are:
efficiency (thanks to autocompletion, there is very little to type), automation (via scripting), more transparency (a GUI may add a layer of obfuscation), stability over time (GUIs tend to change from one version of a program to another), reproducibility (the same command performs the same action, with a limited reliance on memory), customizability.</description></item></channel></rss>