<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>This course on Programming project 2023-24</title>
    <link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in This course on Programming project 2023-24</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Schedule # The course consists of 60 hours of lectures and 30 hours of labs.&#xA;Lectures # By default, lectures are scheduled:&#xA;Tuesday 10:00 - 12:00 Wednesday 08:00 - 10:00 Thursday 10:00 - 12:00 All students attend the same lectures.&#xA;One lecture (to be determined) will be dedicated to a visit to Raiffeisen Information Service in Bolzano.&#xA;Labs # By default, labs are scheduled:&#xA;Tuesday 16:00 - 18:00 Friday 14:00 - 16:00 Students are split in two groups (to be determined) for the labs, with identical content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching staff</title>
      <link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/lecturers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/lecturers/</guid>
      <description>Teaching staff # Julien Corman will teach the lectures and one lab.&#xA;Albulen Pano will teach the other lab.&#xA;Office hours # If you need additional help with the content of the course, the assignments and/or your project, you can ask for office hours with any (or both) of us.&#xA;These appointments must be scheduled via email (follow the links above for our email addresses).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation # Evaluation for this course is based on:&#xA;assignments: up to 30 points, a group project: up to 60 points, and an oral exam: up to 10 points. Your final grade is the sum of the above, multiplied by 0.3.&#xA;Assignments # There will be 8 or 9 assignments for this course. These are standard programming exercises, related to notions seen during the lectures. The labs are (mostly) dedicated to these assignments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Content</title>
      <link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/content/</guid>
      <description>Content of the course # This is a beginner&amp;rsquo;s course on imperative and (class-based) object oriented programming, with an emphasis on practice and collaboration.&#xA;The course relies on Java as main programming language. However, many concepts seen in this course are relevant to other (imperative and/or object-oriented) programming languages: C/C++, C#, Javascript, Go, Kotlin, Lua, Perl, PHP, Python, Rust, Ruby, Typescript, Visual Basic, etc.&#xA;Prerequisites # Students are expected to have completed the Computer Programming course (INF/01 76258).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Board game</title>
      <link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/board_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/board_game/</guid>
      <description>Board game # In order to follow this course, you will need to play one of the two following video games:&#xA;Might &amp;amp; Magic: Clash of Heroes, or Legend of Solgard. These two games have very similar mechanics. So by default, we will refer to them as a unique game (e.g. when we write &amp;ldquo;this game&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;our board game&amp;rdquo;).&#xA;Why this game # Turn-based board games (like chess, go, checkers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unibz-pp-23-24.github.io/docs/intro/sections/bibliography/</guid>
      <description>Bibliography # Java&amp;rsquo;s syntax # In each chapter of this course, you will find Java code snippets that illustrate how to perform certain operations. However, this documentation is far from exhaustive (on purpose).&#xA;So when it comes to syntax, the first two sources of complementary material for this course are:&#xA;the Javadoc of the libraries (standard and auxiliary) used in your project/assignments. Your IDE is often the fastest way to navigate through it, the web.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
